Welcome to this Talk about Fluent Design System from tutorialr.com/talks
Fluent Design System from Microsoft supports a variety of platforms that allows
designers and developers to create coherent experiences
Fluent Design System for the web to create new web apps or adding features to existing ones
Fluent UI is a collection of UX frameworks for creating beautiful cross-platform apps
that share code, design and interaction behaviour
Build apps using the same components as Microsoft from Word and Excel to PowerBI and Teams
with accessibility, internationalisation & performance included
Fluent Design System for Windows makes your apps feel as though they’re designed
with every Windows device in mind such as PCs, Xbox, HoloLens and more
Get documentation, tools and samples you need to get your Windows Fluent apps
published to the Microsoft Store
WinUI allows your Windows apps to be created using the same toolkits that Microsoft
apps do such as Maps, Alarm, Calendar and Photo
Fluent Design System for iOS to design and build custom apps that are natively iOS but still uniquely Fluent
Get documentation, toolkits and guidelines to help get your iOS Fluent Apps published to the App Store
Fluent UI Apple allows you to build apps using the same toolkits used by Microsoft 365 apps
with a library of controls written in Swift supporting Objective-C
Fluent Design System for macOS allows you to build and publish your own Mac desktop apps and add-ins
Find components and guidance you need to extend an existing Microsoft app or create your own
Fluent UI Apple is a native library where you can share the same resources in your own apps or add-ins
as those used by Microsoft 365 apps with a library of controls written in Swift supporting Objective-C
Fluent Design System for Android allows you to build custom apps that are natively Android but still uniquely Fluent
Build apps using controls, resources, toolkits & guidelines
Fluent UI Android is a native library used by Microsoft 365 apps with a library of controls written in Kotlin
Fluent Design System allows building cross-platforms apps and add-ins that work across multiple platforms natively
Every platform has its own look-and-feel and can reference each platform’s toolkit when deciding how to build apps
Fluent UI React Native is a library built using JavaScript and React Native components with a library of controls
written in JavaScript currently supporting Windows and macOS but with iOS and Android support coming soon
Fluent Design System is the latest in the evolution of design language from Microsoft
Windows Mail has had a variety of icons over the years from 2001 through to 2012
where it used the Modern Design Language, then known as “Metro”, introduced with Windows 8
Modern Design Language evolved with the release of Windows 10 in 2015
Windows Mail got a new icon using the Fluent Design System in 2020
Windows Applications such as Alarm, Calendar, Groove Music, Mail, Photos and Tips along with more apps
and services use the Fluent Design System for their look-and-feel and icons
along with other first-party and third-party applications
Microsoft Office has changed its icon as well as the look-and-feel over the years with the
“Jigsaw Puzzle” look of 1995 slowly becoming more modern and abstract
The Modern Design Language in 2012 brought a brand-new icon for Microsoft Office
which has evolved into the current icon in 2019 and applications using the Fluent Design System
Microsoft Office applications such as Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, OneNote, SharePoint
and more have updated icons as well their look-and-feel allowing for a common design across all platforms
including web, desktop, tablet and mobile using the Fluent Design System
Fluent Design System is a cross platform design system that gives designers and developers
the frameworks they need to create engaging product experiences
Fluent Design System features Design Fundamentals with core design principals, patterns,
universal design elements including language, typography, iconography, spacing and colour palette
Design Toolkits with cross-platform design, controls, patterns and templates
to create coherent experiences across a variety of UI frameworks
Fluent Design System can be implemented in code to deliver coherence though controls
and design patterns with UI libraries across a variety of frameworks and languages
Fluent Design System has a hub for samples, examples, reference documentation and style guides
Targets for the Fluent Design System include developing for Web with Fluent UI React,
Windows with WinUI as well as Fluent UI for iOS, macOS and Android you can also Target Windows,
iOS, macOS and Android with Fluent UI React Native
Fluent Design System features System Icons, which are a collection of modern icons from Microsoft
that are friendlier, have rounded corners, simplified shapes and come in regular and filled themes
for both designers and developers, on Figma or GitHub at github.com/microsoft/fluentui-system-icons
Windows features the Fluent Design System with the latest updates to Windows 10 bringing
a refreshed look-and-feel to apps and icons and breathing new life into Windows
and consistency with other platforms such as Web and Mobile
Xbox features the Fluent Design System with recent updates to the look-and-feel of the Dashboard
and consistency with Desktop and Mobile applications that work with the Xbox ecosystem
and features many of the new System Icons
Getting started using the Fluent Design System
Learn about the Fluent Design System, see what’s new and what you can do with Web, Windows,
iOS, macOS, Android and Cross-platform at microsoft.com/design/fluent
Learn about Fluent UI, the collection of UX frameworks for creating cross-platform applications
with Fluent UI React for the Web and Fluent UI React Native for Windows,
iOS, macOS and Android at developer.microsoft.com/fluentui
Fluent Design System include Design Toolkits using Sketch for Web, iOS and Android
as well as an Add-ins Toolkit for Office Add-ins. Design Toolkits using Figma for Web, Windows,
iOS, Android and SharePoint are available along with Fluent System Icons
Add-ins Design Tool kit using Adobe XD is also available
Resources such as Fluent UI can be found on GitHub at github.com/microsoft/fluentui
Fluent Design System gives designers and developers the frameworks they need to create engaging product experiences
Fluent Design System supports platforms including Web, Windows, iOS, macOS, Android as well as
cross-platform to work across multiple platforms with accessibility, internationalisation and performance
Fluent Design System is the evolution of Microsoft’s design language to deliver a consistent
and coherent experience for modern applications for their look-and-feel and icons
Fundamentals for core design principles and universal design elements for Fluent Design System
Toolkits for cross-platform controls, patterns and templates
Libraries across a variety of frameworks and languages
Documentation including samples, examples, style guides and more
Get started with Fluent Design System on Web, Windows, iOS, macOS, Android
and cross-platform at microsoft.com/design/fluent
Fluent UI for a collection of UX frameworks to create cross-platform apps that share code,
design and interaction behaviour at developer.microsoft.com/fluentui
Thanks for watching this talk about Fluent Design System, you can find out more at tutorialr.com/talks/seriesone