Welcome to this Demo of Spotify for Developers on the Uno Platform
using the Fluent Design System from tutorialr.com/talks
The Demo uses Visual Studio 2019 with the Uno Platform Solution Templates
Spotify for Developers with Spotify.NetStandard
and System Icons from the Fluent Design System
The Client Class uses the third-party Spotify for Developers NuGet Package Spotify.NetStandard
and supports HttpClient for WebAssembly along with Image and Paging Methods
Then, the Client Class also has a Method for converting the responses
from the Spotify Client to the Result Class
Next, the Client Class has Methods for getting Categories, Artists, Albums, Tracks
and Playlist Items from the Spotify Client Paging Methods
Also, the Client Class has Generic Methods that wrap all the Paging Methods
for Categories, Artists, Albums, Tracks and Playlist Items
Plus, the Client Class has a Generic Method to List everything from the Paging Method
It also has another Generic Method to List everything as a List of Result Class
and use this with the List Categories Method
Finally, the Client Class has Methods to List Artists, Albums, Tracks, Playlists
and Playlist Items as a List of Result Class along with an Action
The Command Class implements the Methods from the ICommand Interface
to allow for Commanding to be used with the Action from the Client Class
The Config Class has the Client Id and Client Secret which can be obtained from the
Spotify for Developers Dashboard and will allow the Client Class to use the Spotify Web API
The Result Class represents a Category, Playlist, Playlist Item, Album or Track
and includes ResultType for Category, Playlist, Album, and Item which is used for Playlist Items or Tracks
It also has Properties for the Id, Title, Image and Command for Commanding
MainPage includes XAML for a Navigation View with Category, Featured and Released options
including use of Fluent Design System Icons. Content includes an Image with a Border
using Acrylic Effect from the Fluent Design System for the Background
MainPage also includes XAML for a GridView with an Item Template with a Button
which has an Image and a TextBlock using a Fluent Design System Colour
along with a Progress Ring to indicate Loading
The Main Page Class uses the Client Class, where the Country is set for Great Britain
there is an Event Handler for Selection Changed of the Navigation View to List Categories for Category
List Playlists for Featured or List Albums for Released plus a Method for Navigation Result
The Main Page Class also sets the Action to the Navigation Result Method to List Playlists
Playlist Items or Tracks and set the Navigation View to the First option for Category
Universal Windows Platform Demo shows the Navigation View with Category
Featured and Released options along with the Categories from Spotify
Category shows the Categories from Spotify such as the Rock Category
Category when the Rock Category is selected shows Playlists such as the Rock Classics Playlist
Category when the Rock Classic Playlist is selected shows various Playlist Items
Featured, when selected, shows Playlists from Spotify such as Groove Theory
Featured when the Groove Theory Playlist is selected shows various Playlist Items
Released, when selected, shows recently released Albums from Spotify such as Written & Directed
Released when the Written & Directed Album is selected shows the Tracks for the Album
WebAssembly Demo in Microsoft Edge shows the Navigation View with Category, Featured and Released
options along with the Spotify Categories like the Universal Windows Platform Demo
Category shows Spotify Categories such as Rock
Category when Rock is selected shows Playlists such as Rock Classics
Category when Rock Classic is selected shows the Playlist Items
Featured, when selected, shows Featured Spotify Playlists such as Groove Theory
like the Universal Windows Platform Demo
Featured when Groove Theory is selected shows the Playlist Items
Released, when selected, shows Recent Albums on Spotify such as Written & Directed
like the Universal Windows Platform Demo
Released when Written & Directed is selected shows the Tracks for the Album
Thanks for watching this demo of Spotify for Developers on the Uno Platform using the
Fluent Design System, you can find out more at tutorialr.com/talks/seriesone