Welcome to this Talk about Spotify for Developers from tutorialr.com/talks
developer.spotify.com is where you can discover how to build experiences with Spotify for Developers
using Spotify, the music streaming and podcast service
Discover how to develop unique experiences for over 180 million global music fans with Spotify features
such as Audio Features & Analysis, Playback, Recommendations, Search, Playlists, Metadata,
Curated Content and User Taste
Docs contain a complete reference for the Spotify Web API and Web Console allows you to try them
using Sample Data and even obtain an example CURL request to use
Use Cases for common scenarios where Spotify can be integrated include Home Audio using Spotify Connect,
Voice Integrations offering immersive voice-controlled experiences, Wearable devices such as smartwatches,
health and fitness bands plus headphones or Innovate in new and emerging areas
Dashboard is where you create and manage Spotify Integrations, you just need to Log In with a Spotify account
and agree to the Terms & Conditions. Then choose Create a Client Id, then Create an App or Hardware Integration
and state the purpose of the non-commercial integration although Spotify can approve commercial integrations
Once done you get a Client ID and Client Secret to use with the Spotify API
You can also Edit Settings to set the Redirect URI for Authentication
Authorisation will show how to authorise your application to get data
or to allow an end user to approve your application to access their Spotify data or features
Authorised requests to Spotify require permission to be granted to access data. In accordance with OAuth 2.0
the parties involved in the authorisation process are the End User, Application Client and the Spotify Server
Scopes allow your application to access specific API endpoints on behalf of a user such as Images,
Spotify Connect, Playback, Users, Playlists, Library, Listening History and Follow
Obtain authorisation from the user by redirecting to a page where they may log in to Spotify or
sign up if not already, then the requested information is presented including what account data
and activity can be viewed and what actions can be performed
Flows for obtaining app authorisation include refreshable user authorisation,
temporary user authorisation and refreshable app authorisation
Authorisation Code Flow is suitable for long-running applications where the user grants permission only once,
and provides an Access Token that can be Refreshed and is performed on a backend service,
rather than a client such as a browser or mobile app
First, the application requests authorisation where the user logs in and authorises access
Next, the application requests Refresh and Access Tokens with the Code returned in the Redirect URI
Then, use the Access Token to access the Spotify Web API which are set to expire after a short time
Finally, when needed request a refreshed Access Token
Authorization Code Flow with Proof Key for Code Exchange is the best option for mobile
and desktop applications and provides an Access Token that can be Refreshed
First, create the Code Verifier, a cryptographically random string and then hash with SHA256
and base64url encode this to create the Code Challenge and construct and redirect
to the Authorisation URI where the user logs in and authorises access
Next, use the Code returned in the Redirect URI to exchange for an Access Token and Refresh Token
Then, use the Access Token to access the Spotify Web API which are set to expire after a short time
Finally, when needed request a Refreshed Access Token
Implicit Grant Flow is the best option for clients that are implemented entirely on the
client such as a browser however there are no Refresh Tokens provided
First, have your application request authorisation where the user logs in and authorises access,
then the Access Token will be returned as a Hash Fragment in the Redirect URI
and use the Access Token to access the Spotify API
Client Credentials flow is designed for server-to-server communication,
only endpoints that do not access user information may be accessed
Have your application request authorisation and then an Access Token will be returned
in the response and use the Access Token to access the Spotify Web API
Spotify Web API allows applications to retrieve Spotify content such as album data, playlists and more
Spotify Web API endpoints are based on simple REST principles and return JSON metadata about
artists, albums, tracks and more. It also provides access to user related data,
like playlists and music the user saves in their library
Spotify Web API Requests are performed using standard HTTPS requests in UTF-8 format
to an API endpoint and where possible use the appropriate HTTP verbs for each action
Spotify Web API Requests include Albums API such as Get an Album,
Artists API such as Get an Artist’s Top Tracks,
Browse API such as Get All Categories and Episode API such as Get Multiple Episodes
Also, Requests include Follow API such as Get User’s Followed Artists and Library API such as Get User’s Saved Shows
Next, Requests include Personalisation API to Get a User’s Top Artists or Tracks
and Player API to control user playback plus more such as Get Current User’s Recently Played Tracks
Then, Requests include Playlist API such as Get a Playlist’s Items,
Search API to Search for an Item and Shows API such as Get a Show’s Episodes
Finally, Requests include Tracks API such as Get Audio Features for a Track
and User Profile API to Get Current User’s Profile
Spotify Web API Responses are returned in JSON format and with HTTP Status Codes for Success or any Error
Objects Index features the Responses which include AlbumObject, ArtistObject, PlaylistObject,
TrackObject and more or an Error Object
Spotify SDKs are available to help developers take advantage of the Spotify Web API
Web Playback SDK is a client-side JavaScript Library which allows you to create a new player in Spotify Connect
and play any audio track from Spotify in a Web Browser
Spotify iOS SDK allows access to the Spotify API and supports features such as playing a track using the
Spotify App in the background or responding to changes in playback state
Spotify Android SDK allows access to the Spotify API and supports features such as playing a track
using the Spotify App in the background or subscribing to Player State
Third-party SDKs are available for other platforms such as .NET
and the Universal Windows Platform are available on NuGet
Spotify.NetStandard covers the Spotify Web API and is available on NuGet and can be installed
into any .NET Standard 2.0 compatible runtime including .NET Framework, .NET Core and .NET 5
Source Code is available on GitHub including unit tests and documentation
Spotify.NetStandard.Sdk wraps Spotify.NetStandard by adding support for Commanding,
Rich Data Binding enhancements and more making it even easier to build
Spotify applications supporting .NET Standard 2.0 using Xamarin, WinUI and WPF
and is available on NuGet with documentation, unit tests and source code on GitHub
Spotify.Uwp extends Spotify.NetStandard.Sdk by adding dedicated support for
Universal Windows Platform applications including lists as Observable Collections
to support incremental loading allowing for infinite scroll and is available on NuGet
and supports Windows 10 Fall Creators Update from 2017 or later
with full source code, unit tests and documentation available on GitHub
Spotify for Developers allows developers to create their own Spotify powered experiences
developer.spotify.com is where you can get started with Spotify for Developers, read documentation,
try out API calls with the Console and create your Client Id and Client Secret
to use the Spotify API in your applications from the Dashboard and more
Authorisation for the Spotify platform has four flows to obtain application authorisation
Refreshable user authorisation with Authorization Code Flow
and Authorization Code Flow With Proof Key for Code Exchange,
Refreshable app authorisation with Client Credentials Flow
and Temporary user authorisation with Implicit Grant Flow
Spotify Web API endpoints are based on simple REST principles and return JSON metadata about
artists, albums, tracks and more directly from the Spotify Catalogue
Spotify SDKs from Spotify include Web Playback, iOS and Android SDKs
plus there are third-party SDKs available including .NET Standard
and Universal Windows Platform SDKs
Thanks for watching this Talk about Spotify for Developers, you can find out more at tutorialr.com/talks/seriesone